# ALI NEHME, Ph.D.

### Full Stack Developer

📞 +1 438 334-1206 @ ali.nehme@biomedinfo.co 🕜 https://nehmea.github.io/portfolio-fsd/ 💡 Brossard, Canada

#### SUMMARY

As a junior full stack developer, I have experience building applications with a variety of languages and frameworks, including JavaScript, Java Spring Boot, React, NodeJS, Python, Django, and PHP. Besides, I have extensive data science experience and a diverse set of soft skills from 10 years of scientific research in a computational biology. I always strive to bring 100% to the work I do. I look forward to joining a creative and hard-working team where I can grow my skills while pushing projects to success. Available starting from January 2, 2023.

### **SELECTED PROJECTS**

## JobDash



A job application dashboard to search, apply, and follow up with application process.

- · Django, React, Python, JavaScript, Azure Cloud Database, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Role: backend design, Job Post analyzer, unit testing, CV and applications pages
- https://github.com/CocoScrappy/JobDash
- · https://github.com/CocoScrappy/jobdash-front

### Studdy body



A school forum for exchanging ideas and solving problems together.

- · ASP.NET, C#, Razor Pages, EF6, MySQL, HTML, Bootstrap, CSS
- · Role: authorization, User, Forums, Posts, Blob storage
- https://github.com/RamiChaouki/StudyBuddy

### ChatApp



A messaging app/forum similar to Discord with rooms and live messaging.

- · ReactJS, NodeJS, sequelize, MySQL, socket.io, HTML, CSS
- · Role: authorization, live messaging, database management, profile management
- https://github.com/nehmea/2022-WDII-chatApp

# Commons

**#** 08/2022

A website that can serve as a platform for people to share their possessions.

- · Java Spring Boot, JPA, MySQL, Thymeleaf, Bootstrap, CSS
- · Role: project skeleton, database management, authentication and authorization
- https://github.com/SpicyRiceTea/HomingPigeonWD1

# HomingPigeon

**1** 06/2022

A commercial website for selling postcards.

- · PHP, PhpMyAdmin, HTML, CSS
- Role: products page (add to favourites & cart), product info, profile management
- https://github.com/SpicyRiceTea/HomingPigeonWD1

# PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

### **Principal Mentor**

STEM-Away

· Designed workshops and oversaw educative projects in bioinformatics.

# Computational Biology Consultant

# Freelancing

₩ 09/2019 - Ongoing

· Helped private and academic teams design projects and perform analysis.

# Postdoctoral Researcher in Cancer Genomics

### McGill University

🛗 09/2018 - 08/2020 👂 Montreal, Canada

- · Designed a workflow to analyze spatial transcriptomics data.
- · Assisted colleagues and collaborators on eight projects with bioinformatics analysis

# Postdoctoral Researcher in Molecular and Computational Biology

### **University of Tours**

- Designed a workflow for horizontal integration of transcriptomics datasets.
- Delivered results on 12 projects using computational and bench methods.
- · Initiated a project for biomarkers discovery in AML using data science and ML.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### Frameworks

Java Spring	Boot	React	Node	JS	.NET core
ASP.NET	WPF	Razor I	Pages	jQı	uery
Socket IO	JPA	Sequel	ize		

#### Frontend

JavaScript	XAML	HTML	CSS

# ThymeLeaf

#### Backend

Java	PHP	Python	R	C#	Ubuntu

# Database

MySQL	MSSQL	phpMyAdmin	Sqlite
-------	-------	------------	--------

# Hosting

AWS EC2	AWS RDS	XAMPP

# **Project Management**

Github	Microsoft Office	Trello	JIRA
--------	------------------	--------	------

# Data Science

Data Wrangl	ing _	Visualization	Regression
Clustering	PCA	Hypothesis	s Testing

## Large data (>100m data points)

# SOFT SKILLS

Agile	Time management		Teamwork
Present	ation	Self-learning	Flexiblity

### **EDUCATION**

Full-Stack Developer (A.E.C., 1035 hours, Avg 95%)

### John Abbott's College

m 01/2022 - Ongoing

### Ph.D. in Bioinformatics and Pathophysiology

Claude Bernard University Lyon 1

**1** 02/2013 - 11/2015

### TRAINING / WORKSHOPS

# The Data Science Course 2022: Complete Data Science Bootcamp

Udemy, Ongoing

### **LANGUAGES**

English, French, Arabic